Joseph Cooper

Objective

To be in a work environment that challenges me every day, that will allow my unique talents, education work experience to be challenged as I teach others to learn from their challenges and the changes that can occur every day. To overcome company obstacles and create a more profitable and sustainable work environment as a full stack web developer.

Experience

Jan. 2018 - Current (Appliances)

Sept. 2015 - Jan. 2018 (Connections)

Best Buy

Portland, OR

Specialty Sales Manager

- I Run a multi-million-dollar appliance department that produces a 35% direct profit in revenue. We educate and qualify our clients for full kitchen solutions ranging from \$3,000 \$30,000 to help enhance their culinary lives.
- I oversaw, developed and managed a team of 18 employees who cover such categories as Mobile Cell Phones (Sprint, ATT, Verizon and more than 8 prepaid companies), portable audio, smart watches, tablets, and smart home/surveillance products by 30+ manufacturers.
- I analyze, predict and execute on select market trends allowing me to achieve above company expectations in revenue month after month, with an annual revenue of over \$13 million.
- I take it upon myself to lead by example in all areas of the business, from product knowledge to planning for events and executing company directive. By being the expert on this subject, it allows me to better understand and develop on each individual employee's struggles and capitalize on their strengths.

MyBullFrog.Com

St. George, UT

May 2012 – July 2015

Store Supervisor

- Traveling between 3 locations to promote best work habits and train their associates as well as handling of customer escalations and problem solving.
- Understanding of ordering and keeping quality control as well as keeping minimum shelf life of available products.
- Created plans and strategies for pre-orders and phone launches as well as increase in traffic during the holiday seasons.

Feb. 2012 - July 2015

The Yard Dr.

St. George, UT

General Labor

- Layout and design yards for new and existing homes.
- Design and build waterfalls, paths, gardens and laying out sod and gravel.

Education

2011-12, 2014-15 Dixie State University St. George, UT

Associates of Science

Oct. 2021 – Apr. 2022 University of Oregon Portland, OR

Coding Bootcamp

<u>References</u>

Available by request.